<resources>
    <string name="app_name">TourGuide: Wroclaw</string>
    <string name="category_text_view_places">Places</string>
    <string name="category_text_view_museums">Museums</string>
    <string name="category_text_view_about">About</string>
    <string name="category_text_view_parks">Parks</string>
    <string name="wroclaw_about">A city in southwestern Poland, the seat of the authorities of Lower Silesia and Wroclaw. It is located in Central Europe on the Silesian Plain, on the Oder River and on its four tributaries. It is the historical capital of Lower Silesia, as well as the whole of Silesia. It is the main city of the agglomeration of Wroclaw. Fourth largest city in Poland - 637,683 inhabitants, fifth in terms of area - 292,82 km².</string>
    <string name="poland_text_view">Poland</string>
    <string name="wroclaw_text_view">Wroclaw</string>
    <string name="centennial_hall_text_view">Centennial Hall</string>
    <string name="university_of_wroclaw_text_view">University of Wroclaw</string>
    <string name="market_text_view">Market</string>
    <string name="ostrow_tumski_text_view">Ostrów Tumski</string>
    <string name="panorama_raclawicka_text_view">Panorama Racławicka</string>
    <string name="info_centennial_hall_text_view">Wystawowa 1, phone: 071 347-51-00, open: 9 - 16 www.halaludowa.wroc.pl e-mail: zarzad@halaludowa.wroc.pl</string>
    <string name="description_centennial_hall_text_view">Centennial Hall was recognised as one of the greatest architectonic achievements of the 20th century. It was designed to serve the citizens of Wrocław and the guests visiting the capital of Lower Silesia.The monumental building was opened in 1913 on the 100th anniversary of the Battle of Leipzig, won by the anti-French coalition against Napoleon Bonaparte. On this occasion, Wrocław hosted the Centennial Exhibition. Max Berg, the then city architect, designed a massive exhibition hall built with the use of the novel reinforced concrete technology. The dome of the Hall spans 65m and the building is 42m high. The main hall is surrounded by the corridors. It can fit 10 thousand people.The multifunctional space, unconventional construction, interesting and spacious location are only a few of the Halls assets. The Centennial Hall (Hala Stulecia) is currently one of the most wanted places to organise exhibitions, conferences, congresses, cultural and sporting events from Poland and from abroad.Its significance raised considerably in 2006 when the Hall became a part of UNESCO World Heritage List.</string>
    <string name="description_market_text_view">The Rynek of Wrocaw has 3.8ha of surface and belongs to the biggest market places in Poland (the bigger ones are in Kraków and Olecko).Rynek of Wrocław has 3.8ha of surface and belongs to the biggest market places in Poland (the bigger ones are in Kraków and Olecko). However, the Late Gothic Town Hall with its 66m tower is the biggest building of this kind in Poland.  In its underground functions Piwnica Świdnicka, one of the oldest restaurants in Europe.The edifice of the New Town Hall was built in the 19th century. This is where the authorities and the President have their offices. The old Town Hall belongs to the City Museum.Rynek is surrounded by the tenement houses funded by the patricians of Wrocław. The original building, stylistically different from the rest, is a modernist high rise built to the design of Heinrich Rump in 1930.After World War II Rynek went through several changes. In 1956 the statue of Aleksander Fredro was moved from Lvov. In the 70s the tram tracks were closed, the car traffic was heavily limited (the old petrol station was dismantled). The whipping post, destroyed during the war was restored to its original place.In 2000 a fountain was installed on Gołębi Square, in the western part of Rynek, and was called Zdrój from the name of the then President of Wrocław, Bogdan Zdrojewski.The whipping post, the fountain and Fredro´s statue are the most popular orientation and meeting points in Rynek. Another interesting spot are Jaś i Małgosia (Hansel and Gretel), two tenement houses of the altarists (guardians of the altar in St. Elizabeth church) in the north-western part of Rynek.Rynek is also a place of Chirstmas Fairs, New Year’s Eve celebrations, religious, academic and military events. In 2012 Rynek was a big EURO fan zone, gathering as much as 30 thousand people.</string>
    <string name="description_ostrow_tumski_text_view">Surrounded by the river Oder, the old burgh, the origin of the city, has fantastic architecture. The greatest ones are the Gothic St. John Baptist cathedral, rebuilt after World War II and Holy Cross church.There is the Archdiocese Museum there, the oldest historically continuous museum in Wrocław - for over 100 years it has gathered sacral art, which was excluded from cult use and has great historical and artistic value. Among the exhibits one can find Henrykowska Book from 13th-14th century, which contains the first sentence written in Polish.</string>
    <string name="info_panorama_raclawicka_text_view">Jana Ewangelisty Purkyniego 11, 50-155 Wrocław open: wt-nd:09:00–16:00 phone: 71 344 16 61</string>
    <string name="description_panorama_raclawicka_text_view">The painting depicts the Battle of Raclawice in April 1794, in which the Poles won over the Russians. The monumental image is 114 meters long and 15 meters high and was painted in the 100th anniversary of the victory. It is the idea of Jan Styka, a painter from Lviv, who invited Wojciech Kossak, Tadeusz Popiel, Teodor Axentowicz and Wlodzimierz Tetmajer to work on painting. The work lasted 9 months. One of the attractions of Lviv became a rotunda with a panorama of Raclawice, built in Stryjeński Park. The technology used by the authors can be compared with modern 3D technology. The special, panoramic perspective, lighting and stage design constructed before the image make them look multidimensional.</string>
    <string name="church_of_sts_mary_magdalene_text_view">Church of Sts. Mary Magdalene</string>
    <string name="info_sts_mary_m_text_view">Szewska 10, 50-122 Wrocław Phone: 71 344 19 04</string>
    <string name="description_sts_mary_m_text_view">Its interior is quite raw and monumental, with no excess of ornamental elements. In the past, the temple was one of two cityscapes and a resting place for wealthy townspeople. From here there are precious gravestones and numerous medieval and modern epitaphs on the walls of the church. Here their chapels had significant Wroclaw craft features, such as goldsmiths, painters, barbarians and surgeons. Here, teachers and students from the nearby Magdalene Junior High School attended the Mass. Originally Catholic church, in the sixteenth century played an important role in the history of the Reformation in Silesia. It is in this temple that the parish priest, Jan Hess, a disciple of Martin Luther, delivered his first Protestant sermon in Wroclaw. Jan Hess\'s character commemorates the plaque on the outer eastern wall of the church, which was created in 1917, 400 years after Luther\'s Wittemberg speeches. Since 1969, the church serves the Polish-Catholic confession. The most valuable interior furnishings include the late Renaissance pulpit, the work of Friedrich Elder Gross. It is one of the most valuable Protestant pulpits in Europe. Costly materials such as alabaster from quarries near Lwow, Silesian sandstone, gabu and marble were used for the construction. Ambon, supported by figures of angels, decorate scenes from the Old Testament, numerous ornaments and quotations. Its richness associated with the meaning of the pulpit in Protestant churches. It is from here, not from the altar, the clergy taught and preached to the faithful gathered. Next to the altar is a stone, tower sacramentarium from the 14th century, the oldest of its kind in Silesia. At the end of it is placed a figure of a pelican feeding the chicks. A curved, forged staircase leading to the library above the sacristy returns. An exceptionally valuable piece of Romanesque sculpture from the twelfth century was built in the outer southern wall of the church. This is the Portal of Ołbińki, originating from the former Benedictine Abbey, founded by Peter Wlost, and demolished in the 16th century on the orders of the Lutheran city authorities.</string>
    <string name="info_university_of_wroclaw_text_view">Muzeum Uniwersytetu Wrocławskiego pl. Uniwersytecki 1 (gmach Uniwersytetu) phone: 71 375-22-45, 71 375 26 18 e-mail: muzeum@adm.uni.wroc.pl open: 10 -15:30</string>
    <string name="description_university_of_wroclaw_text_view">The Museum is a historical museum and its collections are mainly devoted to the history of the University - from the 15th century to the present. The oldest collections have the registers of Academy Leopoldina but the majority comes from the years after 1811. The Museum (Muzeum Uniwersytetu Wrocławskiego) is situated in the main Baroque building of the Univeristy, designed by Christoph Tausch. It is a historical museum and its collections are mainly devoted to the history of the University - from the 15th century to the present. The oldest collections have the registers of Academy Leopoldina but the majority comes from the years after 1811.</string>
    <string name="park_text_name">Park</string>
    <string name="szczytnicki_text_description">Szczytnicki</string>
    <string name="wschodni_text_description">Wschodni</string>
    <string name="grabiszynski_text_description">Grabiszyński</string>
    <string name="poludniowy_text_description">Południowy</string>
    <string name="brochowski_text_description">Brochowski</string>
    <string name="zachodni_text_description">Zachodni</string>
    <string name="skowroni_text_description">Skowroni</string>
    <string name="lesnica_text_description">Leśnica</string>
    <string name="g_w_andersa_text_description">Generała Władysława Andersa</string>
    <string name="description_the_four_D_D">The Four Denominations District is located...</string>
    <string name="name_the_four_d_d">The Four Denominations District</string>
    <string name="description_the_four_d_d_text_view">The Four Denominations District (Dzielnica Czterech Świątyń) is located in the centre of Wrocław, right next to Rynek. It consists of the area between the streets Kazimierza Wielkiego, Św. Mikołaja, Pawła Włodkowica and Św. Antoniego. It is not a regular, urban district but the unique atmosphere of the place caused that since 1995 it has been called Four Temples District, Four Denominations or Mutual Respect District. Its unique character derives from wonderful sacral architecture. In 300m, close to each other there are: Orthodox church of Nativity of Theotokos, church of St. Anthony of Padua - a Roman Catholic temple, Synagogue pod Białym Bocianem and an Evangelical church of Divine Providence. In 1996 the Council of the Mutual Respect District was created in order to encourage cooperation between the religions. In 2005 the temples were connected with a “cultural route” and the area between them was included in the urban development plan. The District is considered a historical monument. On 29 November 2012 on the corner of the streets Kazimierza Wielkiego and Św. Antoniego the Cristal Planet statue was exhibited. The sculpture created by Ewa Rossano, an artist from Wrocław, became another symbol of the District. The Four Denominations District hosts many cultural and educational events. The Synagogue is a place of special meaning. It hosts many artistic events, every summer there are concerts and exhibitions organised under the name “Summer in The White Stroke Synagogue”. A similar function has the nearby cinema Nowe Horyzonty. It is the first cinema in Poland devoted to artistic films and hosts the most important film festivals in Wrocław. New Horizon Festival and American Film Festival became popular not only among Polish audience but also abroad. Multiple restaurants, cafés, pubs and music clubs situated in the Four Denominations District (for example in the beautiful patio of the Synagogue, surrounded by old walls) make it one of the most magical meeting place in Wrocław.</string>
    <string name="description_henryk_tomaszewski_t_m">The patron of the first Theatre Museum in Poland is Henryk Tomaszewski. This outstanding actor and director was the founder and many years’ director of the Wrocław Pantomime Theatre. Tomaszewski’s and Grotowski’s theatres functioning in Wrocław were top world-class brands. The Theatre Museum is a branch of the Wrocław City Museum. The new museum tells the story of a pantomime and the entire theatre life of Wrocław through permanent and temporary exhibitions, an elaborate and original educational programme combining theoretical and practical activities, meetings, presentations and workshops that will lift the veil of theatre secrets in an unconventional manner. The Theatre Museum is situated near the National Forum of Music. Beside the entrance to the building, the remaining part of the southern wing of the royal palace, there is a bronze sculpture based on Theodor von Gosen’s design presenting the face of Orpheus – a mythical singer.</string>
    <string name="henryk_tomaszewski_theatre_museum_text_view">Henryk Tomaszewski Theatre Museum</string>
    <string name="info_henryk_tomaszewski_theatre_museum_text_view">pl. Wolności 7, Wrocław</string>
    <string name="history_centre_zajezdnia_text_view">History Centre Zajezdnia</string>
    <string name="info_history_centre_zajezdnia_text_view">Grabiszyńska 184, Wrocław zajezdnia.org, biuro@zajezdnia.org phone: +48 717 15 96 00 phone: +48663901767</string>
    <string name="description_history_centre_zajezdnia_text_view">The place of modern historic exhibitions, educational and cultural projects. The exhibition is located in the tram depot and is devoted to the postwar history of Wrocław and Lower Silesia. The place of modern historic exhibitions, educational and cultural projects. The exhibition is located in the tram depot and is devoted to the postwar history of Wrocław, Lower Silesia and other regions annexed to Poland after World War II. A part of the exhibition is to be devoted to national and ethnic minorities that shaped the image of Wrocław and the region. Moreover, the History Centre Zajezdnia (Centrum Historii Zajezdnia) will host temporary exhibitions, devoted to various issues of the postwar history of the city. The exhibitions will be created with the use of the newest techniques and will be attractive and engaging. Thanks to multimedia presentations, space arrangements, light and sound effects, History Centre Zajezdnia will become a place that will present the postwar history of Wrocław in a modern way.</string>
    <string name="description_pan_tadeusz_text_view">The museum presents both permanent exhibitions and an extensive programme of exhibitions and innovative educational activities. The manuscript of the masterpiece by Adam Mickiewicz is not the only attraction. Organized around it is all the remaining 17 topical permanent exhibition rooms, housing 200 historic exhibits, 100 games, applications and animations. There are, among others, rooms devoted to traditional Polish customs - the official, public ones, including government offices and hunting, as well as private, with the culture of home and the table. The museum offers a well designed multimedia exhibition, including the Oculus technology. Thanks to special eyepieces, it allows experiencing a virtual journey in space, mapping of the walls of the museum courtyard, and finally, offers an avatar, which is used for educational activities for children. The well designed corridor (imitating inscription-covered walls from the communist times) will lead us out of the room Powidoki (Afterimages) to the Hall of Witness to History, Władysław Bartoszewski and Jan Nowak-Jeziorański, former director of the Radio Free Europe. Many facilities were also prepared for the visually and hearing impaired, as well as wheelchair users.</string>
    <string name="info_pan_tadeusz_text_view">Rynek 6, 50-117 Wrocław pantadeusz.ossolineum.pl, info@ossolineum.pl phone: +48 717 55 06 00</string>
    <string name="pan_tadeusz_text_view">Pan Tadeusz Museum</string>
    <string name="description_mww_text_view">The exhibition programme of MWW is focused on promoting and popularising the newest local and progressive contemporary art. Since its beginnings in 2011, Wrocław Contemporary Museum (Muzeum Współczesne Wrocław) has been developing social relations with contemporary art by exhibitions, educational events, expanding the collection and creating friendly conditions of participating in art. The exhibition programme of MWW is focused on promoting and popularising the newest local and progressive contemporary art. MWW has a regular programme of debates, lectures, conferences and film screenings and interdisciplinary social projects. In MWW there are publishing promotions and presentations of results of social researches. MWW also conducts scientific projects concerning contemporary problems. The Museum organises educational and artistic workshops for children and adults. The present, temporary building of the Museum is located at Plac Strzegomski, in the old anti-aircraft shelter from 1942.</string>
    <string name="info_mww_text_view">Pl. Strzegomski 2A, 53-681 Wrocław muzeumwspolczesne.pl, mww@muzeumwspolczesne.pl phone: +48 713 56 42 50</string>
    <string name="mww_text_view">MWW Wrocław Contemporary Museum</string>
    <string name="museum_of_pharmacy_text_view">Museum of Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="info_museum_of_pharmacy_text_view">Kurzy Targ 4,50-103 Wrocław muzeumfarmacji.am.wroc.pl, edyta.rudolf@umed.wroc.pl phone: +48 717 84 04 40</string>
    <string name="description_museum_of_pharmacy_text_view">The Museum of Pharmacy in Wrocław is a scientific institution under patronage of Faculty of Pharmacy of Wrocław Medical University. The Museum of Pharmacy in Wrocław (Muzeum Farmacji) is a scientific institution under patronage of Faculty of Pharmacy of Wrocław Medical University. The Museum is devoted to the history of science and development of health and medicine. A chronological order of the exhibition indicates it clearly. From the alchemy workshop in the cellar, through the Renaissance pharmacy on the ground floor, the exhibition devoted to natural medicine and old tools, to the second floor exhibition presenting analytical measuring devices and both synthetic and semisynthetic medicines. The tenement house of the Museum is the only Polish Renaissance-Classicist building and the only place in Poland where, since the second half of the 12th century till the 50s of the 20th century, a private pharmacy had been functioning.</string>
    <string name="royal_palace_text_view">Royal Palace</string>
    <string name="info_royal_palace_text_view">Kazimierza Wielkiego 35, 50-077 Wrocław muzeum.miejskie.wroclaw.pl, kasa@mmw.pl phone: +48 713 91 69 40 phone: +48713916941</string>
    <string name="description_royal_palace_text_view">From 2009 the palace is the main building of the City Museum of Wrocław and presents, among others the exhibition “1000 years of Wrocław”. The Royal Palace (Pałac Królewski) was called Spaetgen’s Palace, from the name of one of the first owners. In 1717 baron Heinrich G. Spaetgen bought a small baroque mansion close to Rynek. After his death in 1750, a Prussian King Frederick II bought the palace. It became a royal mansion, and Wrocław joined Berlin and Königsberg (today’s Kaliningrad) as a residence city. The next Prussian kings extended the palace, changed its design and character. In the middle of the 19th century the palace extended itself from Wolności Square to Kazimierza Wielkiego Street. After the fall of the empire the palace was taken by the city authorities, in the 20s the Palace Museum was opened. During Wolrd War II the building was seriously damaged.</string>
    <string name="the_arsenal_text_view">The Arsenal</string>
    <string name="info_the_arsenal_text_view">Cieszyńskiego A. 9, 50-079 Wrocław muzeum.miejskie.wroclaw.pl, mciesla@mmw.pl phone: + 48713471696</string>
    <string name="the_four_denominations_district_text_view">The Four Denominations District</string>
    <string name="description_the_arsenal_text_view">The City Arsenal is one of the most interesting monuments of municipal architecture in Wrocław. The courtyard is surrounded old warehouses, built between the 15th and 17th century. The City Arsenal (Arsenał Miejski) or St. Nicolas Arsenal (Arsenał  Mikołis one of the most interesting monuments of municipal architecture in Wrocław. Located on the border of the Old Town, behind the medieval walls. An irregular courtyard is surrounded by four old warehouses, built between the 15th and 17th century and two towers which were a part of the walls from the 15th century. For centuries they served as food storehouses and armoury, and since the 19th century as stables and artillery storehouse. One part has been arranged into flats. An ornamental well in the courtyard was built in the 17th c. It is a charming place, abundant with history, not only because of the past of the Arsenal. Today it is a part of the City Museum with the Military Museum and the Archaeological Museum. In summer there are open-air events, concerts and picnics in the courtyard.</string>
    <string name="category_text_view_statues">Statues</string>
    <string name="name_the_swordsman">The Swordsman</string>
    <string name="name_wroclawianka">\"Wrocławianka\"</string>
    <string name="name_train">" A train to the sky "</string>
    <string name="name_waiting">Waiting</string>
    <string name="name_the_burning_sculpture">The burning sculpture</string>
    <string name="name_crystal_planet">Crystal Planet</string>
    <string name="adress_crystal_planet">św. Antoniego, Wrocław</string>
    <string name="adress_the_burning_sculpture">Bernardyńska, Wrocław</string>
    <string name="adress_waiting">al. Juliusza Słowackiego, Wrocław</string>
    <string name="adress_train">pl. Strzegomski, Wrocław</string>
    <string name="adress_wroclawianka">pl. Dominikański 3, Wrocław</string>
    <string name="adress_the_swordsman">pl. Uniwersytecki</string>
    <string name="name_dwarfs">dwarfs</string>
</resources>
